A Guide to the Naomi Benoit Papers, 1981-2002
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
Naomi Benoit Papers 1981-2002
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
M341
1 linear foot.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired from Naomi Benoit in 19 July 2005.
Biographical Information
Naomi Benoit is a member of the Richmond Lesbian Feminists.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1981-2002, of Naomi Benoit principally consisting of the Richmond Lesbian Feminists newsletters and other lesbian-related publications. There are also two response letters written from United States Congressmen Thomas Bliley and Charles Robb concerning gay rights.
Arrangement
Arranged in four series:
Series I. Correspondence, 1991, 1995
Series II. Lesbian Feminist Flyer Newsletters, 1981-1998
Series III. Lesbian Feminist Flyer Operational Files, 1990-1991
Series IV. Lesbian Connection, 1990-2002
Series V. Other Organization's Files, 1998
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1991, 1995 (Folders 1-3)
  Contains letter, 31 January 1995, from United States Representative Thomas Bliley to Naomi Benito (sic.) concerning gay rights; letter, 1 February 1995, from United States Senator Charles Robb concerning employment discrimination and gay rights; and letter, 16 August 1991, from Naomi Benoit to the Lesbian Feminists concerning her opinions on a recent meeting of the newsletter committee.
  Alphabetically
  - Letter from Thomas Bliley, 31 January 1995 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from Charles Robb, 1 February 1995 (Folder 2)
  - Letter to Lesbian Feminists, 16 August 1991 (Folder 3)
- Lesbian Feminist Flyer Newsletters, 1981-1998 (Folders 4-19)
  Consists of copies of the monthly Lesbian Feminist Flyer newsletter.
  Chronological. Folders contain entire year unless months are specified.
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, 1981 (Folder 4)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, February 1985 (Folder 5)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, 1986 (Folder 6)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, November-December 1987 (Folder 7)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, 1988 (Folder 8)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, 1989 (Folder 9)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, 1990 (Folder 10)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, March, August 1991 (Folder 11)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, August 1992 (Folder 12)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, 1993 (Folder 13)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, 1994 (Folder 14)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, 1995 (Folder 15)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, 1996 (Folder 16)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, 1997 (Folder 17)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer, 1998 (Folder 18)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer (partial copies), 1992-1993 (Folder 19)
- Lesbian Feminist Flyer Organizational Files, 1990-1991 (Folders 20-21)
  Comprises an analysis and revision of Lesbian Feminist Flyer budget projections, 1991, and subscription policies, 1990-1991.
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer analysis and revision of newsletter budget projections, 1991 (Folder 20)
  - Lesbian Feminist Flyer subscription policies, 1991 (Folder 21)
- Lesbian Connection, 1990-2002 (Folders 22-81)
  Includes copies of Lesbian Connection, 1990-2002. Issues were published bimonthly. There is also an issue of the Womensbooks News newsletter.
  Chronologically.
  - Newspaper clipping, 1993 (Folder 22)
  - Womensbooks News newsletter, January 1990 (Folder 23)
  - Lesbian Connection, January-February 1990 (Folder 24)
  - Lesbian Connection, March-April 1990 (Folder 25)
  - Lesbian Connection, July-August 1990 (Folder 26)
  - Lesbian Connection, September-October 1990 (Folder 27)
  - Lesbian Connection, November-December 1990 (Folder 28)
  - Lesbian Connection, January-February 1991 (Folder 29)
  - Lesbian Connection, March-April 1991 (Folder 30)
  - Lesbian Connection, May-June 1991 (Folder 31)
  - Lesbian Connection, November-December 1991 (Folder 32)
  - Lesbian Connection, January-February 1992 (Folder 33)
  - Lesbian Connection, March-April 1992 (Folder 34)
  - Lesbian Connection, May-June 1992 (Folder 35)
  - Lesbian Connection, July-August 1992 (Folder 36)
  - Lesbian Connection, September-October 1992 (Folder 37)
  - Lesbian Connection, November-December 1992 (Folder 38)
  - Lesbian Connection, May-June 1993 (Folder 39)
  - Lesbian Connection, July-August 1993 (Folder 40)
  - Lesbian Connection, September-October 1993 (Folder 41)
  - Lesbian Connection, January-February 1994 (Folder 42)
  - Lesbian Connection, May-June 1994 (Folder 43)
  - Lesbian Connection, July-August 1994 (Folder 44)
  - Lesbian Connection, September-October 1994 (Folder 45)
  - Lesbian Connection, November-December 1994 (Folder 46)
  - Lesbian Connection, January-February 1995 (Folder 47)
  - Lesbian Connection, March-April 1995 (Folder 48)
  - Lesbian Connection, July-August 1995 (Folder 49)
  - Lesbian Connection, March-April 1996 (Folder 50)
  - Lesbian Connection, May-June 1996 (Folder 51)
  - Lesbian Connection, July-August 1996 (Folder 52)
  - Lesbian Connection, September-October 1996 (Folder 53)
  - Lesbian Connection, November-December 1996 (Folder 54)
  - Lesbian Connection, January-February 1997 (Folder 55)
  - Lesbian Connection, March-April 1997 (Folder 56)
  - Lesbian Connection, May-June 1997 (Folder 57)
  - Lesbian Connection, September-October 1997 (Folder 58)
  - Lesbian Connection, November-December 1997 (Folder 59)
  - Lesbian Connection, January-February 1998 (Folder 60)
  - Lesbian Connection, September-October 1998 (Folder 61)
  - Lesbian Connection, November-December 1998 (Folder 62)
  - Lesbian Connection, January-February 1999 (Folder 63)
  - Lesbian Connection, March-April 1999 (Folder 64)
  - Lesbian Connection, May-June 1999 (Folder 65)
  - Lesbian Connection, July-August 1999 (Folder 66)
  - Lesbian Connection, September-October 1999 (Folder 67)
  - Lesbian Connection, January-February 2000 (Folder 68)
  - Lesbian Connection, March-April 2000 (Folder 69)
  - Lesbian Connection, May-June 2000 (Folder 70)
  - Lesbian Connection, July-August 2000 (Folder 71)
  - Lesbian Connection, September-October 2000 (Folder 72)
  - Lesbian Connection, November-December 2000 (Folder 73)
  - Lesbian Connection, January-February 2001 (Folder 73a)
  - Lesbian Connection, March-April 2001 (Folder 73b)
  - Lesbian Connection, May-June 2001 (Folder 73c)
  - Lesbian Connection, July-August 2001 (Folder 74)
  - Lesbian Connection, September-October 2001 (Folder 75)
  - Lesbian Connection, November-December 2001 (Folder 76)
  - Lesbian Connection, January-February 2002 (Folder 77)
  - Lesbian Connection, March-April 2002 (Folder 78)
  - Lesbian Connection, May-June 2002 (Folder 79)
  - Lesbian Connection, September-October 2002 (Folder 80)
  - Lesbian Connection, November-December 2002 (Folder 81)
- Other Organization's Files, 1998 (Folders 82-83)
  Includes a gay and lesbian friendly business directory, n.d., and a copy of a report, June 1998, by the Central Conference on American Rabbis, Ad Hoc Committee on Human Sexuality to the CCAR Convention.
  Alphabetically.